# ARSHDEEP SINGH

# Frontend Developer / MERN Stack Developer

**(**+91) 9587975348

@ arshdeepsinghofficial1070@gmail.com @ www.linkedin.com/in/arsh1070

Ganganagar, India

## **SUMMARY**

Software Developer with 2+ years of solid experience working with HTML/CSS, JavaScript & React.js. Also acquired valuable proficiency in backend technologies including Node.js, Express.js & MongoDB. I am a passionate and diligent individual eager to explore new opportunities & committed to continuous learning.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Full stack UI Developer

#### **AECC India Pvt. Ltd.**

**=** 03/2023 - 09/2023 Chennai, India

- Developed Healthinsurancenow mobile responsive web app & implemented the mobile **OTP** user authentication for secure payment process. This app helps students to find & securely purchase the best insurance policies from different insurance companies.
- Implemented the user signin-signup flow in student referral project, integrated with AWS Cognito & used AWS Amplify package for best compatibility.

## Software Engineer

## **PerpetualBlock Technologies**

**=** 01/2022 - 03/2023 Pune, India

- Worked on ArtBanx web app which shows antique and historical paintings with their artists, auction houses, auction prices. Created the automated filter component, which reduces the efforts at UI by 80%.
- Implemented the Image reverse search feature in ArtBanx project to find out duplicates images of artworks which help to reduce data redundancy on database by 85%.
- Implemented the **Report generate** feature in ArtBanx project for artwork fields to checking missing fields, HTML tags, symbols, which improve data quality by 90%.
- Developed Bio-Stock Dashboard project from scratch, created charts to improve data visualization. This project used for Investors to invest in stock of Bio-Pharma companies to understand the drug testing results at different stages, and it's probability of success prediction using Al.
- Developed ProteanPay project for Curia from scratch. This project will be used to make payments in cryptocurrency and generate payment invoices.
- Implemented Advance Search filter feature in Driven project which improve result accuracy by 80%. This product keeps the history of top brands' cars with their performance, launch year, speed, and a lot more.

## Full Stack Web Development Intern

#### **Newton School**

iii 07/2021 - 12/2021 ♀ Ganganagar, India

- Full Stack Web Development along with problem-solving. Learned web development advance technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS & MongoDB.
- Applied hands on learning & Agile development to build a front-end & full MERN stack applications.
- Learned & practiced Data Structure & Algorithms codding questions at
- Participated in various codding contest organized by the platform.
- Debugging & unit testing applications using React Testing Library, Jest, Redux DevTools & debugger.
- Use SonarQube for code quality, check repetition lines of code, code smells & detect bugs in code.
- Worked on various projects such as Spotify clone, News app, Tip-Calculator & Personal portfolio.

#### **SKILLS**

#### Frontend

HTML/CSS JavaScript React.is Next.js Redux **TypeScript Tailwind CSS Material UI Bootstrap** Webpack/Babel **REST APIs** Jest Backend

Node.js/Express.js **MongoDB** .IWT

## Development Tools

GIT GitHub/GitLab **Docker** Jira NPM/YARN **ES6/ES7** Agile/Scrum

# **PROJECTS**

#### StayTune

11/2021 - 12/2021 • Ganganagar, India https://github.com/Arsh1070/StayTune

StayTune app provides real Spotify app experience.

- Developed the Spotify app clone using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript & React.js.
- Integrated the **Spotify APIs** with frontend.
- Implemented the user authentication using Spotify Oauth technique.

## NewsApp

iii 10/2022 - 12/2022 ♀ Pune, India Attps://github.com/Arsh1070/NewsApp

This app provides 6+ different category news with individual user sign-up.

- Developed the News app UI & Backend using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js & MongoDB.
- Integrated frontend with backend for user login & sign-up and also integrated with news.org APIs as third-party for news.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B.Tech In Mechanical** Engineering

**GPA** 6.5 / 10.0

**Rajasthan Technical Unversity** 

# Class XII

**BHOPALWALA ARYA SR. SEC.** SCHOOL

GPA 7.6 / 10.0

**=** 07/2012 - 06/2013

Ganganagar, India